Guide to the Bruce Boling Irish Language Papers AIA.062
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Bruce Boling Irish Language Papers
1905-2001
1970-2000
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Boling, Bruce D. (Bruce Dwight)
Miller, Kerby A.
AIA.062
10 Linear Feet in 9 record cartons and 2 photograph boxes
Bruce D. Boling is a linguist, historian, and librarian whose research focused on the Irish language with specific emphasis on the English dialects spoken in Ulster. He also collaborated with historian Kerby A. Miller on several projects related to Irish immigration history, including Irish Immigrants in the Land of Canaan: Letters and Memoirs from Colonial and Revolutionary America, 1675-1815. This collection documents Bruce Boling's research on the Irish language. Materials include maps, memoranda, correspondence, transcriptions and annotations of research material, journal articles on various aspects of linguistics, and original writing concerning aspects of English and Irish language dialects in Ulster. The collection provides resource materials not only on the history of Irish immigration and the changing nature of regional linguistic patterns, but also the way in which social scientists interrogate the intersection between linguistics and social history. The collection also documents developments in the field of Irish American historiography, including Boling's interdisciplinary focus and methodology.
Separated Materials
Personal materials were separated and returned to the donor after processing.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition Note
Donated by Kerby A. Miller on the behalf of Bruce Boling in 2011.The accession number associated with this gift is 2011.041.
Scope and Content Note
This collection documents Bruce Boling's research on the Irish language. Materials include maps, memoranda, correspondence, transcriptions and annotations of research material, journal articles on various aspects of linguistics, and original writing concerning aspects of English and Irish language dialects in Ulster. The majority of the collection consists of materials produced in the process of researching and contributing to Irish Immigrants in the Land of Canaan: Letters and Memoirs from Colonial and Revolutionary America, 1675-1815, including copies, transcriptions, and translations of 18th- and 19th-century Irish immigrants' letters to family members. The collection provides resource materials not only on the history of Irish immigration and the changing nature of regional linguistic patterns, but also the way in which social scientists interrogate the intersection between linguistics and social history. The collection also documents developments in the field of Irish American historiography, including Boling's interdisciplinary focus and methodology.
Existence and Location of Originals
Much of the collection contains photocopies of letters written by Irish immigrants from the 18th and 19th centuries. Original letters from the collection are located in numerous repositories, including the Belfast Northern Ireland Public Records Office, California Historical Society, Chicago Historical Society, Georgia Department of Archives and History, Illinois State Historical Library, Indiana Historical Society, John Hay Library at Brown University, Kent Library at State University (Cape Girardeau, Missouri), Kildare Archaeological Society, Minnesota Historical Society, National Library of Ireland, New York Historical Society, Perkins Library at Duke University, Public Archives of Canada, South Carolina Library, and Southern Historical Collection at the University of North Carolina. The location of some original letters is unknown.
Historical/Biographical Note
Bruce D. Boling is a linguist, historian, and librarian whose research focused on the Irish language with specific emphasis on the English dialects spoken in Ulster. Boling received a Bachelor's and Master's degree from the University of Iowa, a Master's in Library Science from the University of California at Berkeley, and a Masters and PhD in linguistics with a specialty in Celtic languages from Harvard University. He taught courses in linguistics at Harvard and the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, and held research fellowships at the Dublin Institute for Advanced Studies and the Ulster Folk and Transport Museum. Boling also worked as a language consultant and a librarian at Brown University, the University of Wyoming, the Library of Congress, and the University of New Mexico.
Using immigrants' letters and other sources, Boling sought to reconstruct the Ulster region's 18th- and 19th-century dialects. He also collaborated with historian Kerby Miller on several projects related to Irish immigration history, including Irish Immigrants in the Land of Canaan: Letters and Memoirs from Colonial and Revolutionary America, 1675-1815.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged into three series, one of which has been arranged into subseries. The series are as follows:
Series I. Research Files
Series IA. General
Series IB. Irish Immigrants in the Land of New Canaan
Series II. Original Writings and Presentations
Series III. Secondary Source Materials
All series are arranged alphabetically.
Irish language |x History; Irish Americans -- History.; Ireland -- Emigration and immigration.; Irish language |x Dialects |z Ulster (Northern Ireland and Ireland); Irish language |x Grammar.; Miller, Kerby A.
- Series I. Research Files
  - Subseries IA. General, circa 1970-2000
    Scope and Content Note
    This subseries contains materials related to Boling's research interests and activities not directly related to the publication of Irish Immigrants in the Land of New Canaan. Materials include bibliographic notecards and research notes on linguistic matters not specific to the Irish language, in addition to annotated photocopies and transcriptions of various works of Irish-language poetry and literature.
    - Aidead Muirchertaig Meic Erca, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Allagar Na Hinise (Tomas O'Cronan) Notes and Transcriptions, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - An Druma Mór Notes and Transcripts, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - An Toileán a Tréigeadh (Séan Sheáin í Chearnaigh) Transcription, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - An Toileánach (Toman O'Cronan) Notes and Transcriptions, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Carleton, William Fardorougha the Miser, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Cioth is Dealán (Séamus O'Grianna) Notes and Transcriptions, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Corcán Na Dtrí Gcos (Maidhc Dainín ó Sé) Notes and Transcriptions, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Cré na Cille (Máirtín ó Cadhain), circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Cuimhne Sean-leinbh Pádraig ó Cruadhlaoich) Notes and Transcriptions, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Dúil, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Eochair, Macrí in éirinn (Eamon A Burc), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - The Freeman's Journal (1843-1848), circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Irish Literature: General, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - The Irish Penny Journal, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Jimín Mnaire Thaidhg Pádraig Ó Siochfhradha) Notes and Transcriptions, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Lá Dár Saol (Sean O'Cronan) Notes and Transcriptions, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Le Doux Manuscript, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Leabhar Sheáin I Choraill (Seán Ó Conaill) Notes and Transcriptions, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Leoithre Aniar Transcription, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Lithuania, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Machtnamh Seana-Mhná (Peig Sayers) Notes and Transcriptions, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - McCarthy, Charles. Charles McCarthy's Comic Speaker, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Metropolitan Record (New York, 1861-1863), circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Modern Irish Vowels, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Northern Concord Rule, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Notecards, circa 1970-2000 (Box 10, Box 1, Folder 27-33, Box 11)
    - Nuair a Bhí Me Óg (Seamus O'Grianna) Notes and Transcriptions, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Old Irish Prose and Poetry, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Peig Sayers, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Poor Rabbin's Ollminick (1861), circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Scealta on mBlascaod (Peig Sayers, Kenneth Jackson) Transcriptions, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Seal le Faeili (Sean Faeili Ó Cathain) Transcription, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Suite Gothique Sheet Music, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Tnúthan an Dúchairs: An Braon Brognach (Máirtín Ó Cadhain) Transcription, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - United Irish Cultural Center of San Francisco, Mar 1978 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Subseries IB. Irish Immigrants in the Land of New Canaan, 1959-2001
    This subseries contains materials related to the development and publication of Irish Immigrants in the Land of Canaan: Letters and Memoirs from Colonial and Revolutionary America, 1675-1815, an examination of Irish American migration written and edited by Kerby A. Miller, Bruce Boling, David N. Doyle, and Arnold Schrier. Materials include maps, census data for the time periods researched, notes from research visits to multiple archival repositories, correspondence with the other contributors, and reviews of the publication. The majority of the subseries consists of photocopies, transcriptions, and notes on the hundreds of letters written by Irish immigrants that Boling examined. Many folders contain not only copies of the letters, but extensive analysis of the grammatical, morphological, or phonological features present in these writings. Multiple folders show the process by which Boling and the other historians grouped these letters into distinct categories based on themes, time period, and the letter-writer's profession.
    - Census Date, 1813-1857 from Irish Geography, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Chapter Lists: Agriculture, 1815-1844, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Chapter Lists: Agriculture, 1845-1855, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Chapter Lists: Agriculture, 1845-1869, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Chapter Lists: Agriculture, 1870-1914, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Chapter Lists: British Government Assisted Emigrants, 1815-1844, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Chapter Lists: Business/Commerce, 1815-1844, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Chapter Lists: Business/Commerce, 1845-1869, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Chapter Lists: Business/Commerce, 1817-1914, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Chapter Lists: Business/Commerce and Professions, World War I - Present, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Chapter Lists: Canada, 1845-1869, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Chapter Lists: Canada, 1870-1914, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Chapter Lists: Canadian Settlers, 1845-1869 (II), circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Chapter Lists: Canadian Settlers, World War I - Present, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Chapter Lists: Colonial Revolutionary Period, 1675-1814, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Chapter Lists: Colonial, 1814, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Chapter Lists: Famine, 1845-1877, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Chapter Lists: From Ireland, 1815-1844, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Chapter Lists: From Ireland, 1845-1869, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Chapter Lists: From Ireland, 1870-1914, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Chapter Lists: From Ireland, World War I - Present, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Chapter Lists: Industry/Labor, 1815-1844, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Chapter Lists: Industry/Labor, 1845-1877, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Chapter Lists: Industry/Labor, 1845-1869, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Chapter Lists: Industry/Labor, 1870-1914 (I), circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Chapter Lists: Industry/Labor, 1870-1914 (II), circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Chapter Lists: Industry/Labor, World War I - Present, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Chapter Lists: Military, 1870-1914, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Chapter Lists: Political Exiles, 1845-1869, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Chapter Lists: Post-Famine, 1878-1929, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Chapter Lists: Pre-Famine, 1815-1844, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Chapter Lists: Professionals, 1815-1844, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Chapter Lists: Professionals, 1845-1869, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Chapter Lists: Professionals, 1870-1914, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Chapter Lists: Soldiers, 1845-1869, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Chapter Lists: Voyage/Process, 1815-1844, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Chapter Lists: Voyage/Process, 1854-1869, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Chapter Lists: Voyage/Process, 1845-1869, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Chapter Lists: Voyage/Process, 1870-1914, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Chapter Lists: Voyage/Process, World War I - Present, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Chapter Lists: World War I - Present Addendum, circa 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Chapter Lists: List One, 1845-1869, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Chapter Lists: List Two, 1845-1869, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Chapter Lists: Omitted Documents, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Chapter Lists: Memo on Final Choices, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Cork and Kinsale Archives, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence: General, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence: Libraries, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence: Kerby Miller (I), Jan 1986 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence: Kerby Miller (II), Jul 1986 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence: Kerby Miller (III), Aug 1990 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence: Kerby Miller (IV), Aug 1990 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence: Kerby Miller (V), 2000 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence: Kerby Miller (VI), circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence: Kerby Miller, Regard Wright, Apr 2000 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence: Arnold Schreir, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence: Ulster Folk and Transport, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Geographic Research Notes, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Letters: 18th-Century, circa 1990 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Letters: Alison, Francis, circa 1980-1990 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Letters: Anderson Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Letters: Armstrong, David, circa 1980-2000 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Letters: Ballard, Mrs. Charles, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Letters: Barton, Thomas, circa 1980-1990 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Letters: Beaty, Charles, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Letters: Blair, Samuel, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Letters: Blake, John, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Letters: Breen Family, circa 1980-2000 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Letters: Brown, Samuel, circa 1980-2000 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Letters: Browne Family, circa 1980-2000 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Letters: Buckley Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Letters: Burke, Thomas, 1987-2000 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Letters: Butler Family, circa 1971-2000 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Letters: Cahill, Joseph, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Letters: Caldwell Family, circa 1980-2000 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Letters: Caldwell, James, circa 1980-2000 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Letters: Caldwell, John, circa 1980-2001 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Letters: Callahan, Michael, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Letters: Campbell, Hugh, circa 1980-2000 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Letters: Campbell, Neal, circa 1970-2000 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Letters: Campble, Francis, circa 1980-2000 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Letters: Carleton, Analyzed Excerpts, circa 1980-2000 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Letters: Carleton, Dialect, circa 1980-2000 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Letters: Carleton, Verbal Morphology, circa 1980-2000 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Letters: Carlisle, James, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Letters: Carroll, Charles, circa 1980-2000 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Letters: Carroll, Mary, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Letters: Cashman, Timothy, circa 1980-2000 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Letters: Chambers, John and Jane, circa 1980-2000 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Letters: Christie Family, circa 1980-2000 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Letters: Clarke, John, circa 1980-2000 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Letters: Cleburne Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Letters: Cochrane, Ernest, circa 1980-2000 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Letters: Conroy, Thomas, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Letters: Consular Despatches: Belfast, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Letters: Consular Despatches: Cork, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Letters: Consular Despatches: Dublin, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Letters: Consular Despatches: Galway, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Letters: Consular Despatches: Londonderry, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Letters: Craig, Rev. John, circa 1980-2000 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Letters: Crawford, Alexander, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Letters: Crawford, Gamble, circa 1980-2000 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Letters: Crockett, George (I), circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Letters: Crockett, George (II), circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Letters: Crockett, James, circa 1980-2000 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Letters: Cumming, Mary, circa 1980-2000 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Letters: Cúndún, Pádraig, 1973-2000 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Letters: Curtis, John; Lynch, Hannah; Dune, William, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Letters: Dever Family; Nugent Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Letters: Donovan, Minerva P., 1967 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Letters: Doyle, James, circa 1980-2000 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Letters: Duggan, Mary, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Letters: Dwyer Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Letters: Emmet, Thomas, circa 1980-2000 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Letters: England, John, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Letters: Farmar, Hugh Lovell, circa 1980-2000 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Letters: Ferrakkm Silvester; Reily, Charles Lewis; Johnson, Peter Warren; Croghan, George, circa 1980-2000 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Letters: Fitzgerald, J., circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Letters: Fotterall, Stephen, circa 1980-2000 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Letters: Fullerton, Robert, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Letters: Gamble, Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Letters: Gore-Booth, Reobrt, 1968-2000 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Letters: Grady Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Letters: Graham, George, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Letters: Gray, Nicholas, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Letters: Greenlee, Mary Elizabeth McDowell, circa 1980-2000 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Letters: Greenlees Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Letters: Griffin Family (I), circa 1978-2000 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Letters: Griffin Family (II), circa 1978-2000 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Letters: Griffin Family (III), circa 1978-2000 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Letters: Griffin Family (IV), circa 1978-2000 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Letters: Griffin, Gerald (I), circa 1980-2000 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Letters: Griffin, Gerald (II), circa 1980-2000 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Letters: Guildea, Patt, circa 1980-2000 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Letters: Hall, John, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Letters: Hamilton, Allen, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Letters: Hamilton, W. E., circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Letters: Harold, James, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Letters: Harshaw, N. K., circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Letters: Hayden Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Letters: Hayes Family, circa 1980-2000 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Letters: Heazelton, William, circa 1980-2000 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Letters: Healy, Christopher, circa 1980-2000 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Letters: Hennessy, Maggie, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Letters: Hewitt, Joseph, circa 1970-2000 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Letters: Hill, William, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Letters: Hinds, Thomas, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Letters: Hogan/Dolye Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Letters: Horner Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Letters: Houston, Samuel, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Letters: Hughs Family, circa 1980-2000 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Letters: Johnston Family, circa 1994 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Letters: Johnston, Henry, circa 1980-2000 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Letters: Johson, Job, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Letters: Joyce, John, circa 1980-2000 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Letters: Kells Family, circa 1980-2000 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Letters: Kelly Family (I), circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Letters: Kelly Family (II), circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Letters: Kenney Margaret, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Letters: Keogh Family (I), circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Letters: Keogh Family (II), circa 1980-2000 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Letters: Kennedy, John, circa 1980-2000 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Letters: Kent, Daniel, circa 1980-2000 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Letters: Kerr, Family, circa 1980-2000 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Letters: Kiely, Cornelius and Johanna, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Letters: Kiely, Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Letters: Kierman, James, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Letters: Kiloran Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Letters: King Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Letters: Kirkpatrick, Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Letters: Kirwan, John, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Letters: Kough, Thomas, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Letters: Lalor Family, circa 1980-2000 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Letters: Landy, Mary Ann, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Letters: Largan, Family, circa 1980-2000 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Letters: Lawlor, David S., circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Letters: Lawlor Family (I), circa 1980-2000 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Letters: Lawlor Family (I), circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Letters: Leahy, Tim, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Letters: Letson Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Letters: Liggat, Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Letters: Liggat, J., circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Letters: Lindsey, David, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Letters: Lindsay, Daivid, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Letters: Lough Family (I), circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Letters: Lough Family (II), circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Letters: Lough Family (III), circa 1980-2000 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Letters: Lough Family (IV), circa 1980-2000 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Letters: Lough Family (V), circa 1980-2000 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Letters: Love Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Letters: Maclorg Family, circa 1970-2000 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Letters: Madden, R.R., circa 1970-1980 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Letters: Madden, R.R., circa 1980-2000 (Box 4, Folder 48)